PERSONAL INFORMATION

Maurizio Minieri



- Via B. Cariteo, 59, 80125 Napoli (Italy)
- 3335368000
- mauminieri@gmail.com
- http://mauriziominieri.it in https://www.linkedin.com/in/maurizio-minieri-0b4992174/
- Skype doppiaemme94

Sex Male | Nationality Italian

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Since I was a child I was always curious about the mechanism that resides in things, I was the child who disassembled his expensive toys to see how they worked rather than use them, also the great passion for video games over the years has grown more and more and after attending an experimental scientific high school I enrolled at the University of Naples Federico II, immersing myself in this vast and fantastic world: **computer science**. I am intrigued and fascinated by how it can be present in every object of life, I imagine a future with incredibly immersive video games, holographic video calls, cars that you drive, houses that you clean, stoves that cook, independently.

During my years of university I learned to use various programming languages, to create applications and websites, and thanks to my apprenticeship at DigitalComoedia I developed a passion for a specific branch of computer science: virtual reality.

Here's the virtual reality game I created with ManusVR smart gloves

After graduating I have covered various roles, currently I am:

- PON Expert Professor
- Apple software developer
- Private professor on request

I created <u>my own website</u>, where I express myself. In the <u>TEACHING</u> section you can also consult slides, verifications, guides created by me and see the photos with my students.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2019-2020

Apple Software Developer

Apple Academy, Napoli (Italy)

Acquired skills:

- Teamwork and brainstorming
- Find an original idea, develop it and implement it
- Reflection on the work done and possible improvements
- Presentation of the applications in public and reasoning on the feedbacks received
- Respect for deadlines

2014-2018

Bachelor's degree in computer science

University of Naples Federico II, Napoli (Italy)



Acquired knowledge:

- Techniques of design and implementation of computer systems
- Modern programming methodologies as well as knowledge of programming
- Management of a relational and graphical database
- Development of web and android applications
- Implementation and optimization of algorithms and software systems
- Design and multithreading models
- Usability of the software, in particular prototyping and user interface design
- Computer architecture, operating system and computer networks

Exams taken:

- English
- Mathematical Analysis I
- General Physics I
- Geometry
- Algebra
- Programming I (Language C & C++)
- Architecture of computers I
- Programming II + Laboratory (Language C & C++)
- Numerical calculation
- Elements of theoretical computer science
- Programming languages I
- Laboratory of algorithms and data structures
- Computer networks I
- Operating Systems I
- Algorithms and data structures I
- Databases and Information Systems + Laboratory
- Probability calculation and mathematical statistics
- Economy and business organization
- Software Engineering
- Programming Languages II (Advanced Java)
- Operating Systems Laboratory
- Multimedia information systems

2009–2013 Experimental scientific high school diploma

Scientific High School Niccolò Copernico, Napoli (Italy)

Professional skills acquired:

Mathematics, physics, natural sciences (biology and chemistry). Italian language and literature, Latin, art history, English, history, philosophy, geography, gymnastics and religion. With a program more focused on scientific subjects and practical workshops



WORK EXPERIENCE

2020 Professor National Operational Program at the "Tito Livio" Institute

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

<u>Lecturer</u> in the **EMOCyber & Co** project, module: **Essere e ben-essere cyber**.

2019 Professor of National Operational Program at the State Scientific-Linguistic High School "A. M. De Carlo".

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

Lecturer in the Digit@ISchool project, module: Web Design@School.

2019 Professor of National Operational Program at the "Volino Croce Arcoleo" Institute

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

Lecturer in the **Pensiero computazionale e cittadinanza digitale GENERAZIONE WEB 4.0** project, module: **ROBOTICA**.

2019 Professor National Operational Program at the institute "Nazareth"

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

Lecturer in the Coding a scuola project, module: A scuola di coding.

2019 Professor of National Operational Program at the 76th "F. Mastriani" Institute

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

Lecturer in the **Progettiamo il nostro futuro** project, module: **Roba da Robot**. Lecturer in the **Progettiamo il nostro futuro** project, module: **Robotica per tutti**.

2019 Professor National Operational Program at the "2 Massaia" Institute

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

Lecturer in the ARTE E INNOVAZIONE A SCUOLA project, module: editing e cinematografia III.

2019 Professor of National Operational Programme at the "Giancarlo Siani" Institute of Higher Secondary Education

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

Co-Responsible in the Robotica...mente teaching project.

2019 Professor of Regional Operational Program at the classical state high school "Plinio Seniore"

POR Campania FSE, Napoli (Italy)

Lecturer in the AGORA' SHOW project, module: Informaticando.

2019 Author

of the scientific article:

ManDri: A New Proposal of Manus VR Facility Integration in Everyday Car Driving

2018–Present Private professor

Napoli (Italy)

Curriculum vitae Maurizio Minieri

Lessons:

- Imperative programming languages
- Object-oriented programming languages
- Web programming languages
- Scripting languages
- Robotics

2018 Digital games developer

Apple Developer Academy, Napoli (Italy)

Software developer and project manager in International Space Apps Challange

06/2018–09/2018 Software developer

DigitalComoedia s.r.l., Napoli (Italy)

Acquired skills:

- In-depth knowledge of the C# programming language in the field of gaming and virtual reality using the Unity 3D graphics engine.
- Team leadership
- Problem Solving

Here the game

2016-Present Security Manager

Go2, Napoli (Italy)

2015–Present Security Manager

Manpower, Napoli (Italy)



PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Italian

Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	C1	B2	B2	B2

English

http://www.mauriziominieri.it/static/2020/certificati/ef-set-english.pdf

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages - Self-assessment grid

Communication skills

- Public Speaking
- Grammatical and lexical mastery
- Storytelling skills
- Empathy and listening skills
- Synthesis capacity

Organisational / managerial skills

- Ability to adapt in new contexts
- Ability to work independently
- Ability to work in a team
- Creativity and proactivity
- Empathy and flexibility
- Organization and time management
- Project planning and management
- Respect of the dates
- Stress resistance

Job-related skills

Programming languages:

- **■** C
- C++
- C#
- Java
- Java Script
- Script
- Swift
- Block Programming
- Python

Web languages:

- HTML
- CSS
- PHP

Integrated Development Environment:

- Android Studio
- Atom



Curriculum vitae

- CodeBlocks
- Dev C++
- Xcode
- Netbeans
- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code

Cloud storage:

- Github
- Gitlab
- Dropbox
- iCloud Drive
- Google Drive
- Mega Drive
- One Drive

Frameworks:

- Bootstrap
- Android OS
- NodeJS
- Foundation
- UIKit
- SwiftUI
- Code Igniter

Database Management:

- MySql
- Oracle
- Heidi SQL

Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem- solving		
Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user		

Digital skills - Self-assessment grid

GPU-INDIRE platform expert

Manager:

- Module Card
- Structure
- Class
- Calendar
- Activities

Software:



Curriculum vitae

- Unity 3D
- iMovie
- Sketch
- Camtasia
- Filmora
- Latex
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premiere
- Balsamiq
- Marvel
- Axure
- Matlab
- R
- PowerPoint
- Excel
- Word
- Pspice
- Packet Tracer
- Star UML
- Flowgorithm
- Scratch
- Thunkable
- Thymio VPL
- Cyberduck
- Filezilla
- XAMPP
- Keynote
- Pages
- Garageband
- Numbers

Other skills

- Reliability
- Creativity
- Coaching
- Dynamism
- Motivation and inspiration
- Multitasking
- Resilience
- Self Confidence

Driving licence

В

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Certifications

- Apple Teacher
- Google Digital Marketing





- CISCO CCNA1
- CISCO CCNA2
- GDPR
- Security manager
- International Space Apps Challenge
- New Models of Business in Society
- <u>lgea</u>
- BitDegree
- Google Analytics
- University of Leeds
- Accenture
- Cloud Computing
- Analisi statistica e valutazione del dato sperimentale
- Agile project management
- SCRUM study
- World Health Organization
- EF SET English
- Red Hat

Projects

- The Flying Pig
- My TV
- Not Only Pasta
- GeoAll
- FindOne
- Core Data Library
- API Holidays
- AR Images
- EasyTicket Client
- EasyTicket Operator
- Cabway
- BattleBash
- Change Color
- Personal Manus VR
- Find Your PC
- ABR Tree
- EasyTicket Web
- In the Space
- My Scratch Music
- My Graph
- Highway
- <u>UIL Scuola Napoli</u>

Publications

- ManDri: A New Proposal of Manus VR Facility Integration in Everyday Car Driving
- FindOne
- BattleBash



Maurizio Minieri



References

DigitalComoedia

I hereby authorize the use of my personal details solely for circulation within the company according to the Italian Legislative Decree n° 196/2003

I hereby authorize the processing of my personal data contained in this CV pursuant the EU General Data Protection Regulation 679/2016